

INFORMATION

Address 4D/47 2ND Floor, Old Rajinder Nagar, New Delhi 110060

Phone no-+91-9811940724 Email- gauravmullick@yahoo.com

Date of birth- 16/02/1980 Nationality- Indian Marital Status- Married Gender- Male

SKILL

Cost management
Menu planning
Vendor Development
Manpower Planning
Recipes and Costing
Hygiene management
Leadership skills
Platting and presentation

Gaurav Mullick Sr Executive Chef

PROFILE

Dynamic blend of 20+ years of culinary experience of working across the spectrum as a product developer for 5-star hotels and resorts, cruise liner, fine dining restaurants in India and abroad with core competency of new product development.

STRENGTH

A Chef with 20 years' experience with different hotels such as, Oberois, Carlson, Aman resort, Leela, Carnival cruise, Lemon tree hotels, Dusit international.

- -Potential of exhibiting leadership skills and self -motivation.
- -A quick learner and possess good analytical skills.
- -Able to take challenges. Open to new ideas carry a strong flair for adapting to new environment, demonstrated accomplishment in planning and coordinated assignment.
- -Strong interpersonal skills, able to lead the team to achieve individual as well as organizational goals.
- -I have been experienced in European and Indian Cuisine included plated food also establishing wedding menus and banquet menus for the function, maintained cost, labour and inventory, excellent in customer relations and functions and satisfaction through tasting and events.
- -keeping daily inventory records, ensuring food presentations meet outlined high-quality standards, control the food cost.
- -Enforced strict Hygiene and sanitation policy set by the company.
- -Managing banquet operation of 1000 pax, including central processing unit where all function food is prepared.
- -Expanded Knowledge base for ordering, menu planning and cost management associated with set tasks and executed banquet events as well as offsite catered events.
- -Maintained all policies and procedures put in place by HR department and work closely with them .

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

- Completed my **Certificate in Culinary Practice** from Manukau **Institute of Technology** New Zealand
- Diploma in Hotel Management from Institute of Hotel Management Catering Technology and Applied Nutrition Lucknow, India (1998-2001)
- City and Guilds Certificate in Food Preparation and Culinary Arts
- Completed **STCW95** (Personal survival techniques, personal safety and social responsibilities, elementary first aid, fire prevention and firefighting) approved by **Director General of Shipping India.**
- Completed **Crowd Management Course** approved and authorized by **Bahamas Maritime Authority and Panama Maritime Authority** at Carnival Glory (Vessel of Carnival Cruise lines, Miami U.S.A)

Cuisine Specialization = European and Regional Indian

Brief about European Cuisine

- Sound Knowledge of French, Italian, Mexican cuisine.
- Familiar with European culinary cooking methods products and techniques.
- Knowledge of sous -vide cooking techniques.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded as Star employee of the month in November 2005 in Carnival Cruise Pre-Opening Team Member of the AMAN ,New Delhi Pre-Opening Team Member of the Leela Palace Kempinski, New Delhi Pre -Opening Team Member of the Dusit Devarana Pre -Opening Team Member of Sandal suites, Noida

Reference

Chef Santosh Yadav Executive Chef Aman Resort = Aman -i-Khas Mobile No = 9899715853

Chef Gagandeep Sawhney Executive Chef Shangrila-Banglore Mobile No =9591984039

Chef Amit Sood Multi Property Culinary Director JW MARRIOTT CAIRO and RENAISSANCE CAIRO MIRAGE CITY

Mobile no - + 201227901631

- Sound knowledge of Pre plated exotic meat dishes with combination of their accompaniments and sauces.
- Knowledge of exotic spices, seasonings, marinades, meats and vegetables
- I have opened the restaurant by the name of The Crest at sandal suites its cuisine comprises of Grills, pre-plated western food.
- Experienced in all kinds of cooking styles of Pastas and Pizzas.

Brief about Indian regional cuisine

- Sound knowledge of Indian spices, seasonings, vegetables, marinades
- Familiar with Indian culinary cooking methods products and techniques.
- Strong background in sustained and Indian influenced practices utilized in the culture and cuisine.
- Deep knowledge of Indian gravies and tandoor marination's.
- Extensive Knowledge of North Indian cuisine.
- Sound knowledge of Awadhi, Rajasthani and Kashmiri cuisine.
- Sound Knowledge of Tandoori kebabs and marination's

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sr Executive Chef, Sandal suites, Noida operated by lemon tree hotels (195 suites room property)

Aug 2016 - April 2021

- Taking overall responsibility to efficiently manage and assist kitchen staff of over 50 chefs in producing tasty food to please large number of people in food banquets 'catered events and dining areas.
- Determining the exact quantities of food to be cooked and size of portions and managing budget.
- Regulate and control all departmental expenses.
- \bullet . Identify and communicate food trends and bring those trends to life across the organization through tasting, presentations etc. and managing its budget.
- \bullet Ensuring the highest standards of cleanliness, safety and compliance with hygiene regulations.
- Investigating any customer complaint about food if any.
- Giving training to produce skilled professional experts in all aspects of food preparations of a particular cuisine or a number cuisine.
- Taking part in staff meetings and training activities.
- Support all corporate events both internal and external.

Chef De Cuisine, Dusit Devarana,

New Delhi, Oct 2013 - May 2016

- Interact regularly with guests and cater to their individual preferences and choices to deliver high levels of quality customer care.
- Set up and implement health and hygiene (HACCP) plans including regular monitoring, record keeping and environment friendly waste disposal.
- \bullet Develop creative Menus, conduct quality checks of the food, garnishing and portion size with emphasis on excellence.
- Formulate and implement SOPs for the kitchens, monitor the receipt of items to ensure their quality and regularly inspect the chillers / walk-ins and dry stores to ensure proper storage.
- Worked also on D2 New project of Hotel (216 rooms with 3fnb outlets and banqueting) at Aero City, Delhi.

Jr Sous chef, Leela Palace Chanakyapuri (Pre-opening)

New Delhi, July 2010 - Oct 2013

- Interact regularly with guests and cater to their individual preferences and choices to deliver high levels of quality customer care.
- Set up and implement health and hygiene (HACCP) plans including regular monitoring, record keeping and environment friendly waste disposal.
- Develop creative Menus, conduct quality checks of the food, garnishing and portion size with emphasis on excellence.
- Formulate and implement SOPs for the kitchens, monitor the receipt of items to ensure their quality and regularly inspect the chillers / walk-ins and dry stores to ensure proper storage.

Chef de Partie, THE AMAN, NEW DELHI, (Pre-opening)

New Delhi, Sep 2008- Jun 2010

- Conducting Training Classes for Line Associates to get familiar about Company's Policy & Standard.
- Making Policy & Procedure for Smooth Kitchen Operation
- Making Standard Recipe for Kitchen Menu Prepared by Executive-Chef.
- Preparing food trials for final presentations of the dishes in the menu approved by Executive chef.
- Preparing Market List

Chef De Partie PARK PLAZA, Gurugram

June 2007 - Sep 2008

- Direct Interacting with Guest to take feedback Regarding Quality,
 Standard, Service & Presentation of Food Served to the guest
- Conducting Training Classes for Line Associates to get familiar about Company's Policy & Standard.
- Preparing food trials for final presentations of the dishes in the menu approved
- Planning complete Menus, Preparing Standard Recipes, Ordering Food Ingredients, and Knowledge of Cost Control. Responsible for the Preparation of Complete Meals, Diets

Demi Chef de Partie, CARNIVAL CRUISE LINE

September 2005-May 2007

Commis Chef, QBA BAR AND RESTAURANT

(Awarded as Best Multi Cuisine Restaurant of the Year)

December 2004 – August 2005

- Assisting Chef-De-Partie in A-La-Carte Mise-En-Place.
- Receiving all types of Store from Respective Stores & Stacking & using according to FIFO Method.
- Creating & introducing new dishes for buffet.
- Keeping Records of Kitchen Inventory & Temperature Records of Kitchen.

Commis Chef, HOTEL NIKKO The Metropolitan, New Delhi July 2004-December 2004

Commis Chef KINGS COLLEGE and GUADA AND CATCH RESTAURANT AT MANAKAU, NEW ZEALAND

April 2003 – Feb 2004

Kitchen Manager, KARACHI CATERERS, New Delhi

May 2002 – Feb 2003

Commis Chef, RAJVILLAS JAIPUR (An Oberoi Resort)

August 2001 - April 2002

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Actively participated in Avadh.com held at institute in Kitchen Team.

Represented School in Cricket at State Level.

Represented School in Athletics at Zonal Level.

Actively participated in International Symposium on Automotive Electronics held at IIT Kanpur in Catering Team.

Actively Participated in Chef Competition organized by IHF in Delhi.

Organized German Food Fest at Park Plaza, Gurugram.

Organized many VVIP functions at Hotel Park Plaza.

Actively participated in Bacardi Bartender and Chef Cruise Competition organized by Bacardi Global Travel Retail Division throughout all cruise lines.